let's look now at the allocation of frames
so let's go to the other question we had before
or the other subset of questions
this part is pretty simple so basically you
need to define a minimum and a
a maximum number of frames you can give
to each process the maximum could just be
all the available frames and then you can
define an allocation scheme to be either fixed
or based on priorities is as simple as
the name basically says so with fixed allocation
you can have equal allocation for example you
give the same number of frames to all
the processes
or you can have a proportional allocation which
would be based on the size of the process
here you have a small example so the number
of frames you give is proportional to the
size of the process compared to the sizes
of all the processes you want to run
otherwise you can go for priority allocation
so you can in this case use
the priority of the process which might change
overtime to take decisions on the number of
frames rather than the size of the process
the next thing you need to take into account
when you
think about allocation is about whether you
can only
use frames that belong to the process itself
when we need to replace a certain frame or if
a process can also steal frames from other
ones so if you have global replacement then
a process that requires or that needs a replacement
can pick a frame that belongs also to other
processes
it's good because there are good chances or
higher chances that you can find a frame but
on the other hand you are making the execution
of a process dependent on the execution of
the other processes which still it's not really
a big novelty here we already know that other
processes are also running and they can have
context switches they can be waiting so it doesn't
really matter but still you make it even more
let's say open to what the other processes are
doing or you can go for a local replacement
only so in that case
you can get more consistent better process
performance but you might underutilize memory
if there is another process that doesn't really
need a lot of frames and it has many of them
that are free you could actually steal frames
from that process it would be better so as
always we have these trade offs